A Guide to the David Rockefeller Personal and Professional papers, Rolodex Cards, RG 6 FA249
Rockefeller Archive Center
David Rockefeller Personal and Professional papers, Rolodex Cards, RG 6
1945-2015
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller, David
FA249
22.22 Cubic Feet 101 4x6 card boxes.
Arrangement
Arranged in series as follows: Series 1: Contact Card File; Series 2: Cross-File Cards; Series 3: Trip File; Series 4: Morgue File. Within series all cards are maintained in original order. Alphabetical by last name of individual or business/institution.
Scope and Contents
David Rockefeller's staff at Chase Manhattan Bank maintained a giant 5-foot high rolodex of business, personal, civic, and philanthropic contacts, and a set of this card file was also shared with, and further maintained by, the Rockefeller family office staff at Room 5600. At its height, David Rockefeller's network of contacts was estimated at 100,000 names documented across 200,000 cards.
The collection presented herein is the card files maintained by, and received from, the Rockefeller family office at Room 5600 including additions, revisions, and indexes produced after David Rockefeller's retirement from Chase, and the subsequent closure of his Chase office.
Spanning 60+ years (1945-2008 with some revisions made through 2010), the card file served as: a history record of contacts, relationships, and activities; instant recall for people, places, meetings, events and trips taken; a source of shared information with Room 5600 or others; and as a tool for writing memoirs, press releases and other biographical information. The card index is comprised of four files, represented here as four series, the Contact Card File, its associated Cross-File cards, the Trip File and the Morgue File.
Series 1: Contact Card File (Boxes 1-77)
A Contact Card File card was created each time Mr. Rockefeller met, or otherwise interacted with, a person for the first time. Each card was initially populated noting the date, event and place of the first meeting, with the individual's name, business/organizational/institutional affiliation, address, telephone/fax number(s), home address and personal contact numbers, spouse/partner's name, salutations, educational degrees earned, and any known previous affiliations, or as much information as could be obtained.
Each time David Rockefeller met this person again, another entry was made to the contact card indicating the date, event, place, and any other pertinent information such as other persons attending a given meeting or event. When contacts with a person were frequent, or if Mr. Rockefeller first met the individual years' prior, the person's one card would grow sometimes to 15 or 20 cards, clipped together with the original card.
Contacts with a spouse/partner or guest are usually on the same card. If such contacts were frequent, then a separate card was created for the spouse/partner/guest.
Often a card began with only the person's name, then the rest of the information was compiled, and later maintained through information gathered from a variety of sources including but not limited to: attendee lists from meetings, appointments, dinners/luncheons/galas, membership lists, the New York Times, change of address/affiliation notices, correspondence, and notifications from Room 5600. The Room 5600 messenger would visit the Chase office once a day and provide: the daily schedule (all appointments were posted to the cards and the Desk Diary), trip books (upon completion of trips), and a long range calendar, updated monthly.
Additions and revisions to the Contact Card File continued comprehensively through 2004, with sporadic changes through 2008. Thereafter contacts were maintained in a database (not included), although some manual changes continued to be recorded on the index cards through 2010.
Series 2: Cross-File Cards (The Cross-File Cards currently remain in Rolodex).
Each time a contact card was created for an individual person, a corresponding Cross-File Card was also created to document the person's affiliation (company, institution, university, non-profit, government or government agency, etc.). The cross-file card would include the company name, the event and date of the contact, and the person's name and title.
Any additions, revisions, or changes to a contact card were shared with Room 5600 to ensure that their corresponding set would remain current and active. Revisions to any individual's contact card would often trigger a domino effect that would prompt a change to an associated cross-file card. For example, a change of address or telephone number for a company, would prompt changes on the cross-file card, and corresponding changes to the individual cards for any persons listed on the company card.
As with the Contact Card File, the Rockefeller family office continued to produce and maintain Cross-File Cards through the early 2000s. The Cross-File at RAC was transferred to the archive in the mid-2000s prior to the arrival of the Contact Card File.
Series 3: Trip File (Box 1-13).
Trip books were compiled, and received by the office at Room 5600 upon completion of a trip to facilitate the production of trip cards (pink cards) These trip cards, primarily organized by place and then by name, document contacts made at appointments, dinners, luncheons and any other events attended. They also include information similar to that of the contact cards including personal or business addresses and affiliations when known. Trip books were actively shared with Chase staff to facilitate card production/revision.
Series 4: Morgue File (Box 14-24).
Deceased person's cards were removed from the contact card file, placed in the morgue file, marked with a diagonal line, and updated with a date of death. Additions to the Morgue File appear to have continued through 2015.
Conditions Governing Access
Series 2: Cross-File Cards is open for research. In accordance with the terms of donation from the David Rockefeller estate, Series 1: Contact File, Series 3: Trip File and Series 4: Morgue File are restricted for 25 years from the date of David Rockefeller's death, and will be open for research in 2042.
- Contact File, 1945-2010; 1
  Conditions Governing Access
  In accordance with the terms of donation from the David Rockefeller estate, Series 1: Contact File is restricted for 25 years from the date of David Rockefeller's death (Open in 2042).
  Arrangement
  Original order. Primarily arranged alphabetically by name.
  Scope and Contents
  Series 1: Contact Card File (Boxes 1-77)
  A Contact Card File card was created each time Mr. Rockefeller met, or otherwise interacted with, a person for the first time. Each card was initially populated noting the date, event and place of the first meeting, with the individual's name, business/organizational/institutional affiliation, address, telephone/fax number(s), home address and personal contact numbers, spouse/partner's name, salutations, educational degrees earned, and any known previous affiliations, or as much information as could be obtained.
  Each time David Rockefeller met this person again, another entry was made to the contact card indicating the date, event, place, and any other pertinent information such as other persons attending a given meeting or event. When contacts with a person were frequent, or if Mr. Rockefeller first met the individual years' prior, the person's one card would grow sometimes to 15 or 20 cards, clipped together with the original card.
  Contacts with a spouse/partner or guest are usually on the same card. If such contacts were frequent, then a separate card was created for the spouse/partner/guest.
  Often a card began with only the person's name, then the rest of the information was compiled, and later maintained through information gathered from a variety of sources including but not limited to: attendee lists from meetings, appointments, dinners/luncheons/galas, membership lists, the New York Times, change of address/affiliation notices, correspondence, and notifications from Room 5600. The Room 5600 messenger would visit the Chase office once a day and provide: the daily schedule (all appointments were posted to the cards and the Desk Diary), trip books (upon completion of trips), and a long range calendar, updated monthly.
  Additions and revisions to the Contact Card File continued comprehensively through 2004, with sporadic changes through 2008. Thereafter contacts were maintained in a database (not included), although some manual changes continued to be recorded on the index cards through 2010.
  - A - Al (Box 1)
  - Aldrich - Ame (Box 2)
  - An - Arnold (Box 3)
  - Arr - Bailey (Box 4)
  - Baker - Bartlett (Box 5)
  - Bas - Bell (Box 6)
  - Bengelloun - Bir (Box 7)
  - Bis - Bom (Box 8)
  - Booth - Bre (Box 9)
  - Brennan - Bu (Box 10)
  - Buck - Cahill (Box 11)
  - Camacho - Casey (Box 12)
  - Castro - Cher (Box 13)
  - Chi - Cof (Box 14)
  - Cohen - Correa (Box 15)
  - Corrigan - Cur (Box 16)
  - Curran - Daw (Box 17)
  - Day - De Moraes (Box 18)
  - De Moustif - Dillon (Box 19)
  - Dir - Dud (Box 20)
  - Duell - Ek (Box 21)
  - El - F (Box 22)
  - Fah - Fig (Box 23)
  - Fir - Fox (Box 24)
  - Frank - Gall (Box 25)
  - Gam - Gibb (Box 26)
  - Gibson - Goodman (Box 27)
  - Gordon - Gro (Box 28)
  - Gross - Hall (Box 29)
  - Ham - Has (Box 30)
  - Hat - Her (Box 31)
  - Hes - Holmes (Box 32)
  - Hon - Hunt (Box 33)
  - Hur - Jaf (Box 34)
  - Jaidi - Jones (Box 35)
  - Jones - Kas (Box 36)
  - Kay - Ki (Box 37)
  - Kim - Ko (Box 38)
  - Koc - Kur (Box 39)
  - Kyle - Lau (Box 40)
  - Law - Lev (Box 41)
  - Levy - Lo (Box 42)
  - Lod - Lynch (Box 43)
  - M - Malone (Box 44)
  - Man - Mat (Box 45)
  - Matheson - McE (Box 46)
  - McG - Men (Box 47)
  - Mer - Mir (Box 48)
  - Mitchell - Morgan (Box 49)
  - Morris - N (Box 50)
  - Nak - Nie (Box 51)
  - No - Ol (Box 52)
  - Oliver - Palmer (Box 53)
  - Pan -Per (Box 54)
  - Peres - Pirie (Box 55)
  - Pl - Pu (Box 56)
  - Pur - Reed (Box 57)
  - Reg - Robert (Box 58)
  - Roberts - Ros (Box 59)
  - Rosenberg - Sec (Box 60)
  - Sag - Saunders (Box 61)
  - Sauzey - Schwartz (Box 62)
  - Sco - She (Box 63)
  - Shep - Slim Helu (Box 64)
  - Sm - Spr (Box 65)
  - St - Stuart (Box 66)
  - Su - Tar (Box 67)
  - Taylor - To (Box 68)
  - Todd - Ur (Box 69)
  - Urias - Ni (Box 70)
  - Vill - Walsh (Box 71)
  - Wam - West (Box 72)
  - Wet - Williamson (Box 73)
  - Willis - Wu (Box 74)
  - X - Ze (Box 75)
  - Zi - Zo (Box 76)
  - Seg and Szy and T-Thom (Box 76)
  - Seg and Szy and T-Thom (Box 77)
- Cross-File Cards, 1945-2004; 2
  Series 2: Cross-File Cards (The Cross-File Cards currently remain in Rolodex).
  Each time a contact card was created for an individual person, a corresponding Cross-File Card was also created to document the person's affiliation (company, institution, university, non-profit, government or government agency, etc.). The cross-file card would include the company name, the event and date of the contact, and the person's name and title.
  Any additions, revisions, or changes to a contact card were shared with Room 5600 to ensure that their corresponding set would remain current and active. Revisions to any individual's contact card would often trigger a domino effect that would prompt a change to an associated cross-file card. For example, a change of address or telephone number for a company, would prompt changes on the cross-file card, and corresponding changes to the individual cards for any persons listed on the company card.
  As with the Contact Card File, the Rockefeller family office continued to produce and maintain Cross-File Cards through the early 2000s. The Cross-File at RAC was transferred to the archive in the mid-2000s prior to the arrival of the Contact Card File.
  Original order. Arranged alphabetically by name of business/institution/government or government agency/non-profit/organization/university.
- Trip File, 1950s-2000s; 3
  In accordance with the terms of donation from the David Rockefeller estate, Series 3: Trip File is restricted for 25 years from the date of David Rockefeller's death (Open in 2042).
  Series 3: Trip File (Box 1-13).
  Trip books were compiled, and received by the office at Room 5600 upon completion of a trip to facilitate the production of trip cards (pink cards) These trip cards, primarily organized by place and then by name, document contacts made at appointments, dinners, luncheons and any other events attended. They also include information similar to that of the contact cards including personal or business addresses and affiliations when known. Trip books were actively shared with Chase staff to facilitate card production/revision.
  Original order. Primarily arranged by place and further arranged by name.
  - Bhutan - 2003 Trip through Yugoslavia (Box 1)
  - Ivory Coast through Papua New Guinea (Box 2)
  - Algeria through Niger (Box 3)
  - Nigeria through Sudan (Box 4)
  - Bermuda through Switzerland (Box 5)
  - Honduras through Cyprus (Box 6)
  - Tanzania through Zimbabwe (Rhodesia) (Box 7)
  - Germany (Box 8)
  - Egypt (Box 9)
  - Trip Booklets - British Virgin Islands through Kuwait (Box 9)
  - Trip Booklets - Panama through Thailand (Box 10)
  - Trip Booklets - United Arab Emirates (UAE) (Box 11)
  - Trip Booklets - USA - Ft. Worth through Virginia (Box 11)
  - Trip Booklets - USA - Indiana through Delaware (Box 12)
  - Trip Booklets - USA - Cleveland through Michigan (Box 13)
- Morgue File, 1950s-2015; 4
  In accordance with the terms of donation from the David Rockefeller estate, Series 4: Morgue File is restricted for 25 years from the date of David Rockefeller's death (Open in 2042).
  Series 4: Morgue File (Box 14-24).
  Deceased person's cards were removed from the contact card file, placed in the morgue file, marked with a diagonal line, and updated with a date of death. Additions to the Morgue File appear to have continued through 2015.
  Original order, alphabetical by last name.
  - A - Brace (Box 14)
  - Bracht - Cross (Box 15)
  - Crossland - Ferguson (Box 16)
  - Fernald - Hand (Box 17)
  - Handler - Josephy (Box 18)
  - Joslin - Lyons (Box 19)
  - Maass - Mosbacher (Box 20)
  - Moscoso - Powers (Box 21)
  - Prado - Schoenrich (Box 22)
  - Schoff - Tobin (Box 23)
  - Todd - Zwach (Box 24)